

Vineyard, UT 84059, 307-389-9307 jason.e24@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative and knowledgeable software engineer with solid background in web development. Background in designing, developing, and deploying software for client and server-side applications. Proven experience working in a fast paced environment with changing requirements and deadlines.

SKILLS

- Programming languages (Python, JS/TS, C++, Java, C#)
- Frontend frameworks (Angular, React. React Native)
- Team Collaboration

- API development and integration (FASTapi, Django, .NET frameworks)

- · Critical thinking

- Database Management (SQL, Postgres, MongoDB)
- Continuous Integration/Deployment
 Software testing and debugging
 - Leadership

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

August 2023 - Current

- UAMPS | Salt Lake City, Utah
- Designed, developed, tested and deployed new features and functionality using CI/CD best practices.
- · Adapted software, capitalizing on emerging technologies.
- Led development of new products including UAMPS Alerts Mobile app, and new UAMPS API's utilizing React, React Native, and FASTapi.
- · Coordinated with multiple departments to improve software capability to fit changing needs.
- Developed and tested automation tools for testing and quality.
- · Continued maintainance of existing software through bug fixes and enhancements, technologies include Multivalue databases (noSQL)...NET framework, and frontend HTML.JS.CSS.

Software Engineer

July 2022 - August 2023

Opentext | Provo, UT

- · Led front-end Angular development for new product release and refactoring UI on existing products (Over 70,000 lines of code contributed to various projects, mostly in Angular).
- Kept up to date on web development and design trends using UI/UX best practices (Material UI).
- · Tested and improved code coverage for various repositories.
- Developed scripts to speed up process of completing various tasks.
- Resolved 100+ defects through close collaboration with quality assurance team.
- · Mentored 3 junior developers, facilitating their growth and knowledge acquisition.

Software Engineer Intern

May 2022 - July 2022

- Microfocus (Opentext) | Provo, Utah
- · Contributed to team sprint planning and project meetings.
- Identified and automated test cases and improved existing integration testing processes.
- Tested and improved code coverage for various repositories.

Freelance | Vineyard, UT

- Attracted users to websites with professional, user-friendly designs and clean code for high-performance operation, using HTML, JS, CSS/SCSS.
- Detected problems provided by client's feedback and implemented solutions.
- Developed websites with accessibility and compatibility for different browsers.

Account Executive July 2015 - June 2021

Vivint Inc | Provo, UT

- · Accomplished multiple tasks in a fast-paced environment.
- Boosted sales numbers by diligently tracking and analyzing trends to identify strategic opportunities.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) - Software Engineering Utah Valley University, Orem, UT

May 2024

Associate in Science (A.S.) - Computer Science Utah Valley University, Orem, UT

December 2022